On this clip I want to talk about grids, grids are a light modifier, if you look at that, see how it kind of disappears when I turn that.
They do the same thing to the light.
The light shines through, let me get this turned on, light shines through and when it's not on there it gives a broad light dispersion.
As you can see, as I put this on it narrows the beam down considerably.
It actually just funnels the light down to a smaller beam.
Grids are a couple of different sizes, I don't know if you can see this, as you can see this one has much finer holes in it than this one, this one narrows the beam even more.
This one is a little coarser and allows a little more.
This is very, very important when you are trying to do very fine detailed lighting because it allows you to put light exactly where you need it.
These are amazing little things.
You can make some of these out of cardboard, by cutting cardboard sidewards and then like putting a rubber band or something around them.
The problem is, your modeling lights will cause them to burn so you have to be really, really careful, you cannot leave your modeling light on a long amount of time if you make your own.
These are all kind of specific to the size of your reflector, they just snap in on the Speedtron, on the Photogenics, they actually have a little clip, a little spring loaded clip that holds them in.
And they work real well, they will last you a lifetime, you cannot drop anything on it, because it will smash the little honeycombs that's inside.
If they get to where they are spilling light a little bit too much you can come in with flat black paint and spray them and it will keep the reflection off, from spilling where you don't want it.